<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Crystal Palace Festival 2013</title>
	<subtitle>The Crystal Palace festival has been running successfully for the last six years. In 2011, it expanded to Westow Park, with a live music stage, food and craft stalls, arts workshops, sports and kids’ activities, adding to the many events around the Triangle.</subtitle>
	<link href="http://balupton.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
	<link href="http://balupton.com" />
	<updated>2013-06-16T15:07:24.623Z</updated>
	<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org</id>
	<author>
		<name>Nick Rowlands</name>
		<email>nick@rowlando.com</email>
	</author>

	
		<entry>
			<title>Take a little escape thanks to The Little Escape</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-15-take-a-little-escape-thanks-to-the-little-escape"/>
			<updated>2013-06-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-15-take-a-little-escape-thanks-to-the-little-escape</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;div class='img-caption-right right'&gt;
    &lt;img src='/images/blog/2013-06-15-little-escape.jpg' alt='Karen and Lilja from The Little Escape' width='250' /&gt;
    &lt;span class='caption'&gt;Karen and Lilja&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top of Westow Park is set to be transformed into an oasis of tranquility on Saturday 29 June, as our holistic 
tent, sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://thelittleescape.com/&quot;&gt;The Little Escape&lt;/a&gt;, offers a little escape from it all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Little Escape is a team holistic therapy project, a group of people with lots of different training and
 experience, but who are all passionate in believing that wellbeing is something to share and to strive towards&amp;quot; says 
 acupuncturist and business owner Lilja Katanka. &amp;quot;We work together in genuinely wanting to help individuals find the 
 right treatment for them at that time, and working together works so well both for the practitioners and the 
 patients - so it is holistic on lots of levels! We want to offer a place for people to learn about their own health 
 and bodies, and to be able to relax and just generally feel better.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many activities taking place throughout the day you won&amp;#39;t want to leave..! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We&amp;#39;ll be offering taster treatments of chair massage and Indian head massage, which are festival favourites, Shiatsu 
stretches and sleep and relaxation workshops, a free Sound Bath session, mini reflexology, and facial tasters,&amp;quot; says Lilja.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Alongside our specialists, who will be on hand to answer any questions you have, Veronica Massa will be displaying her 
beautiful handmade organic aromaceutical products for face and body, &lt;a href=&quot;http://thelittleescape.com/products/massaholistics/&quot;&gt;Massaholistics&lt;/a&gt;; we&amp;#39;ll be running a free
prize draw, and offering discounts on a range of therapies and products.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being a relatively new business in Crystal Palace this is their second year of being a festival sponsor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We jumped at the chance to be platinum sponsors as it&amp;#39;s such a fantastic event that gets the whole area involved, 
we&amp;#39;re really happy to support this.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;For us it&amp;#39;s really important to meet people, so that we can explain what we do and show that we&amp;#39;re real people who
 are passionate about our work, and our involvement with the community. I also think that when people are curious 
 about treatments or therapies it can be intimidating, so we love having the opportunity to give advice or 
 recommendations, and encourage questions.&amp;quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Personally I can&amp;#39;t wait for the festival! I was brought up in Crystal Palace, and I&amp;#39;m constantly amazed and 
impressed at how much it&amp;#39;s changed over the years... it feels like the festival is a celebration of this evolution..!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>A volunteer tells us their story - a rewarding experience</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-14-a-volunteers-story"/>
			<updated>2013-06-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-14-a-volunteers-story</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get involved&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;#westow-house&quot;&gt;find out this Saturday at Westow House&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/2013-06-14-karen-pernyes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Karen Pernyes&quot; class=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Crystal Palace Overground Festival is run by a dedicated team of volunteers. Everyone, including the musicians,
artists and performers, donate their time and talent for free. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volunteers have an enormous impact on the health and well-being of communities. It sounds rather clichéd, but the
festival really wouldn't happen without them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crystal Palace resident Karen Pernyes has volunteered for the festival for the past 3 years, here's her story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;I first became involved in 2011, a few months before the first festival in Westow Park,&quot; says Karen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;I work closely with the festival director, Noreen Meehan, to make the event a success. From working together to set
up and run the open community consultation, writing the job descriptions of all the key organisational roles, to
taking on the specific role this year of operations director for the main outdoor event at Westow Park on Saturday 29 June.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;On the day I will be the one in Festival HQ glued to the end of a two-way radio!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;But it's not about taking on as much as I or others take on, we need every bit of help we can.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Volunteering at the festival is a wonderful way for the whole community to come together, even if it's just
sticking up a few posters in a local school, helping for a few hours on the day, spreading the word, supporting
the events and traders, or lending a hand to organise next years event, so that we can have many more great festivals ahead of us!&quot; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Volunteering gives a huge sense of pride and achievement - there is nothing better than seeing the looks on all
the volunteers faces on the day with a sense of 'I did this, I was part of this, I helped make this happen'.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to our brilliant team of festival volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote style=&quot; background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0.3); padding-bottom: 1px; border-left: none;&quot; id=&quot;westow-house&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can't do it without you!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We are having a very special stall at Westow House pub in Crystal Palace this Saturday (15 June) between 12-4pm with more information about volunteering for the festival plus the guide is out, copies of the Transmitter and lots of other info!&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Come meet some of the team and ask any questions you might have have – thanks to Justin &amp;amp; Co. at Westow House for hosting us and supporting the festival!&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://crystalpalacefestival.org/volunteer&quot;&gt;crystalpalacefestival.org/volunteer&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>The Transmitter Magazine takes centre stage</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-12-the-transmitter-magazine-takes-centre-stage"/>
			<updated>2013-06-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-12-the-transmitter-magazine-takes-centre-stage</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Theatrics, curiosities, and delights, have been blended perfectly with this year&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;/whats-on/saturday-29-june/performing-arts/&quot;&gt;Performing Arts tent&lt;/a&gt; sponsored by 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetransmitter.co.uk/&quot;&gt;The Transmitter magazine&lt;/a&gt;, which takes to the stage at Westow Park on Saturday June 29. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We are over the top happy to be sponsoring the Performance Art Tent, which will be showcasing an eclectic mix 
of local talent and oddities, just like the magazine really!&amp;quot; states editor Andy Pontin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nestled at the bottom of Westow Park, you will be transported back to a Victorian era with the talented cast 
performing their very own and original interpretation of &amp;#39;The Great Exhibition&amp;#39;, which lies at the very 
heart of Crystal Palace!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Transmitter itself is also helping spread the word of the festival far and wide, &amp;quot;The summer festival 
themed issue hits the streets Friday June 14, and includes a 12 page festival &amp;#39;What&amp;#39;s on Guide&amp;#39;. I&amp;#39;m really 
pleased with this issue and it looks great, thanks to our designer Simon Sharville&amp;quot;, adds Andy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/blog/2013-06-12-tt28-cover.jpg' alt='The Transmitter cover' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Transmitter has been 100% behind Noreen Meehan, chair of the festival, since she got involved, and we 
have been a sponsor since the first Overground festival.  It&amp;#39;s been great to watch her from the sidelines 
magnificently managing to produce such fabulous and well organised events. The Transmitter is unilaterally 
declaring independence for Crystal Palace next issue and we are going to recommend Noreen as our first Queen, 
even though she is technically foreign.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see the festival as one of the &amp;#39;planks&amp;#39; in the Crystal Palace structure, one of a growing number of cultural 
reference points that help people feel a part of something. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside hanging out near the Performance Art Tent, watching all the fun, and soaking up the atmosphere, I&amp;#39;m 
looking forward to seeing Metamono on the &lt;a href=&quot;/whats-on/saturday-29-june/bands/&quot;&gt;music stage&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#39;ve featured them in this month&amp;#39;s edition of
the Transmitter, and I&amp;#39;m very much looking forward to watching them live for the first time.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>The Electric Palace open air cinema returns!</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-10-the-electric-palace-open-air-cinema-returns"/>
			<updated>2013-06-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-10-the-electric-palace-open-air-cinema-returns</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have a rare treat in store for Crystal Palace lovers and historians of the wondrous palace
itself – our open air cinema at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.uk/maps/preview#!q=Cooper&amp;#39;s+Yard%2C+London+Borough+of+Lambeth%2C+London+SE19&amp;amp;data=!1m4!1m3!1d557!2d-0.0823727!3d51.4202038!4m11!1m10!4m8!1m3!1d4825851!2d-4.064941!3d53.800651!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!17b1&quot;&gt;Coopers Yard&lt;/a&gt; will show &lt;em&gt;The Pleasure Garden&lt;/em&gt; (1953),
a BBC short film, on its 60th anniversary. Filmed among the ruins of the Crystal Palace terraces, The
Pleasure Garden is a poetic ode to desire. Made by the American poet James Broughton, the film features
Hattie Jacques and Lindsay Anderson, with John le Mesurier as the bureaucrat determined to stamp out
any form of free expression. Lovers of the history of Crystal Palace will find much to treasure in this
time capsule of a film, which shows the Crystal Colonnade and the bandstand (both later demolished), the
Royal Naval Volunteer Reserve Memorial, and much of the statuary that was to be auctioned off in 1957.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This special event will be followed a screening of the Oscar nominated, BAFTA winning short, &lt;em&gt;A Morning Stroll&lt;/em&gt;
by Crystal Palace’s own Grant Orchard. This animated short film tells the story of one New Yorker’s early
morning encounter with a chicken, an event that plays out over 100 years...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This special event will be followed by the main feature &lt;em&gt;Little Miss Sunshine&lt;/em&gt;. What happens when you stuff a failed
motivation speaker, his wife, the nation&amp;#39;s number one Proust scholar, an elderly potty-mouthed heroin addict, a
teen who&amp;#39;s mute by choice, and a bespectacled little pageant hopeful into a mini VW bus for a three day road trip?
You get this hilarious but moving satire about a dysfunctional family obsessed with winning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy tickets -&lt;/strong&gt;
Please go to &lt;a href=&quot;/whats-on/friday-28-june&quot;&gt;Friday&amp;#39;s event page&lt;/a&gt; to purchase tickets. The ticket costs £7.50 and includes free drink on arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With thanks to our sponsors&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Crystal Palace-based Kinopto are a tech-startup developing a new service for the global film-screening market. They
have created a digital delivery and playback system to bring highquality cinema to any public venue, with films
available just weeks after cinema release&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>So, how did this new festival design come about…?</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-07-how-did-this-new-festival-design-come-about"/>
			<updated>2013-06-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-07-how-did-this-new-festival-design-come-about</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/2013-06-07-cpof-design-team-web.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Design Team&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year the festival likes to refresh its identity, and with the assistance of three very talented local Crystal 
Palace designers, they came up with year&amp;#39;s design, which bases its origins firmly in Vintage Crystal Palace and 
its 1970s musical heyday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rick Walker (graffiti artist), Graeme Dalton (fine arts) and Gillian Hibbs (illustrator) all brought their own 
unique styles together to create the live and vibrant, typography based design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative director of Paintshop Studio, Rick Walker, said: &amp;quot;I have always been a fan of the festival and it&amp;#39;s 
been great to be involved and work with some of the other creative people in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We all wanted to get involved, and it was a great experience to combine our ideas, influences and skills. It 
really was a collaborative effort and started by agreeing to go down a typographic route for the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Each of us sketched out hand-drawn typefaces onto tracing paper and then met to overlay them and see what 
combinations worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I then photographed these and brought them into the computer to create the layout, detail text and add the 
colour. The process of photographing hand drawn images tends to give a very nice natural feel to the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This was a new approach for us all, but it seemed like a very natural and organic way to design and felt 
really appropriate for the Crystal Palace Overground Festival.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We feel the new branding really hits the mark in appealing to a very diverse audience – quite a difficult brief 
to nail, but the team did a brilliant job and we are thrilled with this vibrant homage to Crystal Palace past and present.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Invasion of the gate-crashers by Joe Duggan</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-05-invasion-of-the-gate-crashers"/>
			<updated>2013-06-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-05-invasion-of-the-gate-crashers</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/joe-at-foodstock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Joe Duggan At Foodstock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all the best ideas it started with some gate-crashing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoke yesterday to El Crisis and David J Pugilist, the two guys who gate-crashed our last Spoken Word event and left
us all reeling with their word play. Very hard to pin down their styles: David has a hyperactive delivery with strange
pauses and jumps, almost like someone is mixing him live.  Despite having played some of the biggest venues in
spoken word, including Glastonbury and Random Acts on Channel 4, he&amp;#39;s very excited about playing at the festival
with his partner in rhyme El Crisis.  I think he&amp;#39;s starting to pick up on the Crystal Palace magic. El Crisis is
very hard to define too: hip hop, chanting and a hint of old spiritual, there&amp;#39;s something hypnotic going on. You
might have heard him on BBC Radio, caught him at Glastonbury or on Sky Arts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After they finished gate-crashing so eloquently we knew we had to have them back. And get a bigger space!
So we&amp;#39;ve decided to pull out the stops for our Overground Special on Friday 28 June at 7:30pm so its now upstairs
in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.antennastudios.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Antenna Studios&lt;/a&gt;. The spoken word events at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cafething.tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Antenna Café Thing&lt;/a&gt; have been building momentum for the last few months
and it&amp;#39;s time for a best of the best night with some of the most exciting performers we&amp;#39;ve had so far. There&amp;#39;s even
more to celebrate as this Overground Festival is happening a year after the Café Thing launched. Hard to believe
that this venue, with Georgie Cooke at the helm, which has built up such a reputation for intimate music and spoken
word gigs, has only been going for a year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as David J Pugilist and El Crisis we are asking back a host of great performers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Tamsin Kendrick featured on our first night and danced a clever line between all her different identities: Croydon
    woman, Oxford graduate and a definite hint of Jessica Rabbit. Highly commended in the Forward Prize and featured at
    Latitude &amp;quot;Explores the terrains of love and faith with unflinching directness and refreshing honesty&amp;quot; Niall O&amp;#39;Sullivan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  The Jazzman has entered the building: Jazzman John Clarke has won over crowds all over London with his sheer enthusiasm
    and energy, and we keep asking him back!  &amp;quot;When it&amp;#39;s good, jazz poetry is really goosebumpy, joyous stuff. 
    And Jazzman is one of the best we&amp;#39;ve seen&amp;quot; The Londonist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Kellie Gillespie took us to some strange places last time, and left us reeling, laughing and chained to her bedposts. 
    Her kinky karaoke of ex-lovers as performed by the audience was something to behold! &amp;quot;One of the most exciting 21st 
    century writers in the UK&amp;quot; Edward Timon, The Erotic Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as hosting, I will also do a few poems myself ...&amp;quot;Under the chatty vernacular is a lovely, casual sharpness. 
Joe&amp;#39;s poetry is like an unexpected hot chilli in something sold as sweet&amp;quot; Cherry Smith, Poetry Editor Brand Magazine. 
Cherry always had great taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And one of the really special things about these nights have been the brilliant open-mic slots: local people 
getting up and taking a chance and reminding us again what a ridiculously talented area Crystal Palace is. 
Well one of our open mic-ers needs a feature slot so Zulie Stenson, who moved us with her beautifully honest and 
intimate love poems will be treating us to more.  We also have a limited number of open mic-slots available – email 
me at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x69;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#116;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#58;&amp;#x6a;&amp;#111;&amp;#x65;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&amp;#x67;&amp;#103;&amp;#97;&amp;#x6e;&amp;#50;&amp;#x31;&amp;#x35;&amp;#x40;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#116;&amp;#x6d;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#x2e;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#x6d;&quot;&gt;&amp;#x6a;&amp;#111;&amp;#x65;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&amp;#x67;&amp;#103;&amp;#97;&amp;#x6e;&amp;#50;&amp;#x31;&amp;#x35;&amp;#x40;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#116;&amp;#x6d;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#x2e;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#x6d;&lt;/a&gt;  for more info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where will you be on Friday 28 June and what better way could you set yourself up for the rest of this brilliant festival?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Kids’ Zone bursts with activity thanks to Smash Bang Wallop!</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-02-kids-zone-bursts-with-activity-thanks-to-smash-bang-wallop"/>
			<updated>2013-06-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-06-02-kids-zone-bursts-with-activity-thanks-to-smash-bang-wallop</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Building on their involvement with the festival in previous years, we are pleased to announce
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashbangwallop.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Smash Bang Wallop&lt;/a&gt; as the main sponsor of our (bursting at the seams!) Kids&amp;#39; Zone, taking place at 
Westow Park on Saturday, June 29.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only will the kids be busy with a record number of activities – &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2013-05-15-kids-zone-preview/&quot;&gt;Kid&amp;#39;s zone preview&lt;/a&gt; - taking place, but Smash Bang
Wallop are playing host to a huge array of festival activities themselves, with their passion for dinosaurs
at the heart of everything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#39;Dinosaurs are the love of our life!&amp;#39;, says owner Liz Clamp. &amp;#39;Our shop just isn&amp;#39;t complete without them!
Whether they are featured on a t-shirt, a birthday gift, or are a plush soft toy, we can&amp;#39;t survive a day
without one hanging out in the shop somewhere!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/2013-06-02-sbw-dino.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Smash Bang Wallop Dino&quot; class='right' width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#39;We will be letting one out on Saturday to visit the activities tent in Westow Park!&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#39;Don&amp;#39;t forget to pop by to our Crystal Palace themed stall outside our shop on Westow Street  on your way to the park.
We&amp;#39;ll also be selling Ray Stanbrook tea towels, cards and prints, as well as launching a (currently) top secret t-shirt!&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#39;We&amp;#39;re also part of the triangle traders day on Sunday, where a £50 gift voucher will be awarded to the person who
can identify the age or designer of a number of specially selected items located around the store&amp;#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#39;We are really excited about the Festival, it&amp;#39;s a fabulous community event bringing new people to the area and
reminding the rest of us why we&amp;#39;ve made Crystal Palace our home. Each year it gets better and better so go forth;
listen to the music, eat the food, shop the shops and bask in the atmosphere that is Crystal Palace&amp;#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Introducing the Antenna Studios Café Thing</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-05-30-introducing-the-antenna-studios-cafe-thing"/>
			<updated>2013-05-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-05-30-introducing-the-antenna-studios-cafe-thing</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/cafe-thing-2013-05-30.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cafe Thing&quot;  /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather symbiotically, the Crystal Palace Overground Festival is happening at approximately one year since
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.antennastudios.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Antenna Studios&lt;/a&gt; opened its &lt;a href=&quot;http://cafething.tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Café Thing&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s been a
wonderfully abundant year that&amp;#39;s quickly established the café as a solid venue for great art exhibitions,
poetry, folk, soul, jazz, rock and experimental music. Notable additions to our intimate café space thus
far have included Jono McCleery, Tanya Auclair, Daisy Beau, Nathaniel Robin Mann and Julia Biel, as well
as local acts and events including The Lovebirds, Breezy &amp;amp; the Spaceshipman, Cloudier Skies, Franck &amp;amp; Dani,
Kellie Gillespie, Joe Duggan &amp;amp; RPM Club, some of whom will perform as part of the festival programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daily, we&amp;#39;re known for brewing great filter and Aeropress coffee with beans from Volcano, Brett &amp;amp; Bailey&amp;#39;s now
infamous baked goods, an eclectic and somewhat experimental bagel menu and a fully stocked bar including a
selection of Ales and Antenna specials such as our refreshing Cucumber G&amp;amp;T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Café Thing whose name reflects the Icelandic roots of the studios director and means &amp;#39;meeting place,&amp;#39; also
frequently hosts ecologically and environmentally minded events and workshops from Goldsmith&amp;#39;s students and CP’s
Transition Town. Not without a huge amount of gratitude from us, they, The Secret Garden, local residents, friends
and Capital Growth have supported us in our efforts to green the Antenna Studios Yard which is now home to a whole
host of edible plants and flowers that when harvested will find their way into our drinks and food menu. We&amp;#39;re
proud to serve the traders, shoppers and perusers at Crystal Palace&amp;#39;s buzzing Local Food Market situated in the
car park next to Antenna Studios every Saturday from 10am-3pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s the magic and talent of CP&amp;#39;s magnetic triangle that motivates and drives us and it&amp;#39;s this that, with your
help, we aim to celebrate as part of the Crystal Palace Overground Festival this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Festival programme (in brief)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday - Poetry and Spoken Word in the Gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday- RPM Club - Mind the Gap Special&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunday - All day Café Sessions + BBQ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Antenna Studios Café Thing is located at Bowyers Yard, Haynes Lane, Crystal Palace SE19 3AN.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open: Weds-Fri, 11am-8pm. Sat 9am-8pm. Sun 11am-7pm. Events until 11pm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Lover of Creating Flavours sponsors food tasting tent</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-05-19-lover-of-creating-flavours"/>
			<updated>2013-05-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-05-19-lover-of-creating-flavours</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/anita-clare-field.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Anita Clare Field&quot; width=&quot;138&quot; class=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the huge success of A Taste of SE19, the food tasting tent at last year’s Crystal Palace Overground
Festival, Anita-Clare Field, founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.loverofcreatingflavours.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Lover of Creating Flavours&lt;/a&gt;,
leapt at the opportunity to come on board as this year’s tent sponsor, one of the many specialist areas in
Westow Park on Saturday June 29.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food is Anita’s passion whether it’s writing about it for her phenomenally successful food blog, or experimenting
in the kitchen with family and friends, food is at the heart of her life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m passionate about encouraging people to steer clear of the confines of a recipe by adding ingredients to
their own personal taste, to create a unique gastronomic delight to tantalise the tastes buds,” says Anita.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve lived in Crystal Palace for the last 25 years and I think the festival’s a wonderful thing, it has the
local community at its heart, from supporting local businesses, to creating an event the whole family can enjoy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m really excited to be involved this year, and very much look forward to sharing our exciting and diverse
programme with you all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To whet your appetite, our food demonstrations and tastings will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beer &amp;amp; Cheese&lt;/strong&gt; delights from Manish Utton-Mishra of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/goodtastefd&quot;&gt;Good Taste Food and Drink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tour the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crystalpalacetransition.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Crystal Palace Transition Town&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Edible Garden&lt;/strong&gt; with Rachel de Thample, before turning your handpicked crop into delicious dishes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn how to make the Brazilian national dish&lt;/strong&gt;, feijoada, with Mariana Camarotte of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.braziliana.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Braziliana café&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Afternoon tea gets a makeover&lt;/strong&gt; with Jayne Totty of &lt;a href=&quot;http://supernourished.com/&quot;&gt;Supernourished&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mauritian street food&lt;/strong&gt; comes to life thanks to Selina Periampillai, creator of &lt;a href=&quot;http://yummychooeats.com/&quot;&gt;Yummy Choo&lt;/a&gt;, Mauritian cuisine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wind down with our &lt;strong&gt;cocktail hour demo&lt;/strong&gt;, before continuing the evening by visiting one of the many award-winning
bars and restaurants around the Crystal Palace triangle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to seeing you all very soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.loverofcreatingflavours.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Lover of Creating Flavours&lt;/a&gt; We deliver original or classic recipes with a twist either from our own
notebooks or from our fantastic contributors or guest bloggers.  We deliver expert information from people at
the sharp end of the food business, farmers, small business or Chefs. All of us united in our desire
to deliver the best in food and drink.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Special kids' zone preview! Our volunteers get excited!</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-05-15-kids-zone-preview"/>
			<updated>2013-05-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-05-15-kids-zone-preview</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Rachel D&amp;#39;Cruze and Veryan Wilkie-Jones share their programme for this year&amp;#39;s Kids&amp;#39; Zone at Westow Park - “Keep
them busy, keep them interested and mostly keep them entertained!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think we&amp;#39;ve managed to get something for
everyone and so we hope you&amp;#39;ll love what we&amp;#39;ve put together. Having a dedicated Kids&amp;#39; Zone this year certainly 
has made life easier, and we feel we&amp;#39;ve created a mini kids&amp;#39; festival full of delights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a dedicated Sporty
Area including hulahooping, tootball, space hoppers and Zumba throughout the day, to our Performance Tent with 
Rockmount Primary Children&amp;#39;s Choir to open, followed by drama, music, dance performances and a fantastic piece 
of theatre turning your kids into detectives with Detect Egg from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simplysmileyproductions.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Simply Smiley Productions&lt;/a&gt; – what&amp;#39;s not to like?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah but that&amp;#39;s not all...we have also brought our story telling tent to life with local authors and illustrators, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.faber.co.uk/catalog/author/alex-milway&quot;&gt;Alex
Milway&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.garynorthfield.com/&quot;&gt;Gary Northfield&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timsharville.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Tim&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://acarrotinthetoaster.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Marion&lt;/a&gt; Sharville but also including a fab programme from Upper Norwood Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More you cry! Okay so for the artist in you, visit our Arts Tent! We have a two hour mosaic workshop from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.art4space.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Art4Space&lt;/a&gt;,
plus &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bluesparrowsartclub.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Blue Sparrow Art&lt;/a&gt; and Artstastic. Still not enough??? Well, what would an event be without a bouncy castle?
Yep oh and we&amp;#39;ve managed to get two – one for the little &amp;#39;uns and one for older kids. Face painting, 
you ask? Yes, all courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://glitterbees.com/&quot;&gt;Glitterbees&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/DoXasFaceAndBodyArt&quot;&gt;Doxa&lt;/a&gt;, all rounded off with a kids&amp;#39; disco in the main tent
courtesy of the Wilky Bar Kid &amp;amp; Finlay (aged 6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly but not leastly, huge THANKS go to our Kids&amp;#39; Zone sponsors local Crystal Palace shop &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashbangwallop.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Smash
Bang Wallop&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; we couldn&amp;#39;t have done it without you. Detect Egg from Simply Smiley Productions has
been individually sponsored by local businesses, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sellitmama.com/&quot;&gt;Sell It Mama!&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cpsic.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Physiotherapy Solutions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>What's happening with the programme this year?</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-05-11-festival-programme-this-year"/>
			<updated>2013-05-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-05-11-festival-programme-this-year</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Noreen Meehan, chair and programme director for the festival, gives us an update about
all the hard work going on organising 2013&amp;#39;s festival:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s all going really well but as
    usual there&amp;#39;s a mad dash to get everything confirmed in time to do a great marketing campaign.
    I am chasing around the Triangle to get all of the traders&amp;#39; and venues&amp;#39; events into the
    printed guide and the park programming is just about finished. We should have a final
    programme up on the new website around 16 May, fingers crossed! There are lots of new
    initiatives this year as we have had a wonderful team of volunteers come on board – more
    than ever before – which means we can do more! Our local businesses have also come up
    trumps sponsoring and advertising with the festival and we have some grant money too so it&amp;#39;s all really good.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;New things in Westow Park on Saturday 29 June include a performing arts tent,
    a dedicated kids&amp;#39; zone with more activities than ever before and even more bars which is of
    course very important! Not forgetting the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crystalpalacefoodmarket.co.uk/&quot;&gt;farmers&amp;#39; market&lt;/a&gt;
    from our great Transition Town that will be happening in Haynes Lane on that Saturday. I have personally been working with
    lots of fab people around the Triangle, our venues and traders, to get our new Triangle day on
    Sunday 30 June off the ground and I am very excited about all the activities we are able to
    put on with their help and support! Look out for more on this day but we can reveal that
    there will be a vintage event in Church Road, a fine art and craft fair in Haynes Lane, a
    fitness fun event in Victory Place, Grooveschool are doing DJ skills workshops for young people
    and that doesn&amp;#39;t even include all the traders&amp;#39; events and stalls plus loads of excellent live
    music and food from the pubs and venues around the area. So I think it might be best if you
    all took the Monday off work – I know I will be! Looking forward to seeing you all there!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Volunteering is good for your soul&amp;hellip; and for your heart</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-04-24-volunteering-is-good-for-your-soul"/>
			<updated>2013-04-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-04-24-volunteering-is-good-for-your-soul</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/volunteers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent research has shown that giving time and energy to help others not only makes people feel good, but it has a direct and positive effect on physical wellbeing.  So why not do some good for yourself and your community and apply to volunteer this year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seasoned volunteer Cathy Henchion shared with us some of the opportunities for participation in this year's Crystal Palace Overground Festival.  She is recruiting volunteers from the community and has opportunities for people of all ages: from stewarding around the main outdoor stage in Westow Park on Saturday 29 June, to
supervising the Kids' Zone and meeting and greeting visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;We're looking for passionate, fun-loving volunteers, aged 18 and over to
ensure this year's community arts festival is bigger and better then ever
before.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cathy started working with the Festival three years ago. &quot;There are so many reasons to get involved,&quot; says Cathy.  &quot;It's great to be a part of something, to make things happen.  You get to make new friends and it's also good fun.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volunteers come from every age group from 18&amp;ndash;70 years old.  &quot;It's a chance to encourage collaboration between the generations.  The combination of energy and enthusiasm combined with the opportunity to learn and participate in a group venture makes it a truly social experience.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many, the success of London 2012 was due in part to the army of volunteers who gave up their time and energy to ensure that the Olympics were such a great success.  There may have been physical benefits for the volunteers too.  Being big-hearted can help to reduce cholesterol levels and body mass index, according to a new study in the Journal of the American Medical Association.  Canadian researchers found that volunteering work not only reduced risk factors like cholesterol and body fat, it also reduced associated factors like stress by improving self esteem, mental health and mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The festival kicks off with a wide range of fringe events at venues around
Crystal Palace on June 27 and 28.  &quot;We're particularly keen for people to come forward and volunteer as Stewards at Westow Park on Saturday 29 June and the Upper Norwood Triangle on Sunday 30.  You could volunteer to be a Steward for as few as 4 hours,&quot; says Cathy. &quot;You're there to help if needed but you will still be able to enjoy the Festival even 'on duty'.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can spare a few hours on one of the festival days, then please do &lt;a href=&quot;/volunteer/&quot;&gt;let us know via the volunteer form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Overview of Community Consultation, December 2012</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-01-12-overview-of-community-consultation"/>
			<updated>2013-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2013-01-12-overview-of-community-consultation</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The consultation evening brought together a wide range of local people who looked to review previous festivals, list all the stakeholders of the festival and identify the aims, objectives and priorities for the festival going forwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A summary of each point and common threads can be found below and you can &lt;a href=&quot;/documents/2012/festival-community-meeting-report-2012-12.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Festival Community Meeting Report December 2012 (PDF 32KB)&quot;&gt;download the Community Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Review of previous festivals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were lots of positive comments! Many specific points were raised that need to be picked up by this year&amp;#39;s team, when in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other common threads were to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase diversity, e.g. more for teenagers, more diversity of music, seating for older people.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the date: some strong calls to stay in June, several calls to move it later again.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve specific aspects: from communication with groups to marketing to more toilets!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review timings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call to strengthen the festival outside the park and re-address the balance between park and triangle.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stakeholders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stakeholders of the Crystal Palace Festival range from the community as a whole, to all the local community groups, businesses and organisations with a link to Crystal Palace, including transport organisations; plus local government, schools and other statutory bodies and funding bodies. The full list should serve to help the new organising committee. Stakeholders make up the list of not only who the festival is for, but who can help make it a sustainable success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Aims and objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consultation asked people to write down what they felt should be the aims and objectives for the festival in 2013. There was a fair amount of overlap with the comments written down when we asked everyone for their priorities for the event.  However, in this section, key points that found common ground were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bringing the whole community together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;having fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the promotion of Crystal Palace, its people and all it has to offer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the full report for some other great points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Priorities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was much crossover with the section on Aims and Objectives, but in this section, the words &amp;#39;showcasing&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;promoting&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;supporting&amp;#39; Crystal Palace and what it has to offer – both the place and the people - were often mentioned as was the importance of bringing the community together and appealing to the widest possible range of people.  Beyond the clear common ground, there was a range of brilliant points made for the new organising committee to try to live up to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ideas section of the consultation was set aside from the main event with the point made that many ideas will not make it to become a reality without someone to take it forward. Hopefully those who attended and others who can help organise the event can come forward to take roles and help make these ideas happen!  Please come forward now if you can volunteer to join the organising team and make the festival in 2013 simply brilliant!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Interview with The Hipster Ray</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-06-11-interview-with-the-hipster-ray"/>
			<updated>2012-06-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-06-11-interview-with-the-hipster-ray</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Local band and Palace champions the Hipster Ray take to the stage in Westow Park at 1.45pm on Saturday, be prepared!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the story behind The Hipster Ray?&lt;/strong&gt;
A jam in an overgrown back yard in south London brought several like-minded mods and punks together
who decided to tear up the pub/club circuit with original music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did that name come about?&lt;/strong&gt;
It’s the name of a song we wrote about a happy bloke who brings smiles and laughter wherever he goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe your sound in 5 words:&lt;/strong&gt;
Punky lashings of original beats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are most of you based in Crystal Palace?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes, we all are..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like most about the area?&lt;/strong&gt;
All hail to to everything in the Palace, this unique corner of south London has been good to us and we want to continue to repay it over the bar and through microphones..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we can expect from your set at the Festival?&lt;/strong&gt;
Be afraid.. anything can and probably will happen…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/_3ZA40YpXLc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Interview with Elia and the Low Tears</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-06-10-interview-with-elia-and-the-low-tears"/>
			<updated>2012-06-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-06-10-interview-with-elia-and-the-low-tears</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The interviews keep coming with Elia and the Low Tears! Get to know a bit about them before you check out their set next weekend…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the story behind the name The Low Tears?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Low Tears means big, fundamental human emotions. Like what you feel when you eat ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Musical inspirations?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;We love great pop songwriting, as well as funk and soul and rock. All the sounds that are mixed up in our music. We would like to think of ourselves as the resulting love child of a night of passion between Prince and Joni Mitchell and Aretha Franklin and Talk Talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us a secret you know about South London.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;It’s the best place for birthday morning pancakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you looking forward to about the Festival this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;We’re expecting a great atmosphere. There seems to be lots of fun things happening and it looks like it will be relaxed and unpretentious. Plus obviously we’re looking forward to ramping people up with our noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your song Perfect Circles has quite a tongue in cheek music video. Is that the kind of thing we can expect from your set at the festival this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;We won’t have a live feed on video screens of mad fans dancing to us in real time on the internet, on this occasion. The show is pretty full on. High voltage and funky with hooks. We like to make sure tailfeathers get shook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/VCxD-PitYiA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;463&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Heads Hearts Interview</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-06-09-heads-hearts-interview"/>
			<updated>2012-06-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-06-09-heads-hearts-interview</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another of our awesome bands, &lt;a href=&quot;http://headshearts.com/fr_home.cfm&quot;&gt;Heads Hearts&lt;/a&gt;, took some time to answer a few quick questions about their music and how they&amp;#39;re gearing up for the festival. Get to know Amber Taylor-Groves (ATG), Lynne Porterfield (LKP) and Abby Tythe (ABS)  before they rock out for us next weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I love the description of Heads Hearts on your website! That kind of attitude shines through in your music. What/who are your musical inspirations?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATG: Anyone that is good, I know that sounds cliché but it&amp;#39;s true. I love pretty much every type of music, but these are just a few: Florence and the Machine, Daft Punk, Mike Snow, Basement Jaxx, Tina Turner, Prince, Donna Summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LKP: I like a whole lotta styles of music from Black Sabbath to Emmylou Harris to Four Tet to The Jackson 5. In a weird way I think we are a blend of all of the above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABS: I&amp;#39;m pretty much inspired by anybody that can whack a drum. Although I&amp;#39;m always in awe of Matt Helders (arctic monkeys drummer). That dude knows his stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did the band get together? Are you all from around South London?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATG: HH was formed about 3 years ago by me and a very good friend of mine. We spent 8 months solid writing and recording a lot of material together and we took it on the road and receive a great response. A year or so on and I decided that I wanted more musicians on stage and my partner in crime had to leave the stage due to family commitments. I already knew LKP &amp;amp; Abs through friends and they had been to quite a few gigs, so I decided to see if they fancied joining me to make some noise. There was born the new Heads Hearts.
I am the only one that&amp;#39;s from South London but LKP does live around the corner from me now which is very cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LKP: Amber and I now live down the street from each other but I&amp;#39;m from East London and originally from San Francisco so I&amp;#39;m the token Yank. Abs is rockin&amp;#39; the Essex thang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABS: We&amp;#39;re from all over the place but I used to go and watch Heads Hearts before Lynne or I were part of it. I met Amber through a friend and she asked me if I fancied hitting stuff down the studio with her and Lynne. I jumped at the chance, I was pretty nervous but managed to get involved and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have been some musical highlights for the band so far?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATG: Getting to hang out with these girls and play to packed out rooms of people dancing around like lunatics, you&amp;#39;ve got to be happy with that. But the same thing is at the top of the list for all of us on this one, I&amp;#39;ll let LKP explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LKP: A festival we played last year was a real moment. Mainly because we were subjected to torrential rain all weekend but when we hit the stage at sunset the sun came out and backlit the uber enthused crowd. It was nice to see so many smiling faces out there… it was probably that they were drunk but hopefully the sun and the music added a little something. Apart from that, every HH gig is a highlight. It&amp;#39;s so much fun playing with these two ladies. They are ridiculous.com!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABS: There have been loads! We&amp;#39;ve been together a year now and we&amp;#39;ve come on leaps and bounds. Playing a festival at sunset was quality. There was even a tear in my eye. Oh and making the video to “in my blood” was a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How would you describe Crystal Palace in five words or less?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AT-G: We all answered these questions separately and the girls sent me their answers. This is genuinely what the pair of them sent back to me unbeknown to each other ‘Crystaly &amp;amp; palacey&amp;#39;. So I guess that has to be our answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can festival-goers expect from a Heads Hearts set?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AT-G: A proper high energy show. Because we all love what we do I think that really shines through on stage. Our main aim is to make people enjoy themselves, it doesn&amp;#39;t take too much ‘making&amp;#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LKP: We&amp;#39;ll get your blood pumping, your heart thumping and your ass jumping. (Plus we won&amp;#39;t have any rhymes that terrible in any of our songs!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ABS: Pure entertainment, Amazing energy, a good mixture of electro sounds and live instruments. Oh and a bouncy little lady belting out some blinders on the stage. That&amp;#39;s what I reckon but come see for yourself :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/5201853?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>John Blood and the Highlys Interview</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-06-08-john-blood-and-the-highlys-interview"/>
			<updated>2012-06-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-06-08-john-blood-and-the-highlys-interview</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With less than a week to go til the festival, we’re getting pretty excited here at Overground Festival HQ. Stay tuned to the blog for last minute news and updates. But first, get to know a few of the bands taking to the stage next Saturday! First to be interviewed is John Blood from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/jbandthehighlys&quot;&gt;John Blood and the Highlys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the story behind ‘The Highlys’? How did that name come about?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I (John) was looking to start a band after years of doing solo open mic stuff. We’ve known each other for about two years, some of us for more. We’re a group of friends who love and enjoy making and playing music together. We had been looking for a name for some time. ‘The Highlys’ was one of many names floating around, we chose it because it sounded cool at first, but we’ve grown into it. It sums up how lucky we feel about being alive, having love in our lives and making music!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With 8 members, your influences must be pretty varied! Who are your musical inspirations?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;We come from all over, and not just all over the UK! With members from the Caribbean, France, UK and West Africa there are a lot of influences, but I would say as a group reggae, blues, calypso, soukous and afrobeat are what we are influenced most by when making music. But even then there are elements of other genres. It’s a universal thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us a secret you know about South London.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;If I told it wouldn’t be secret ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are most of you based in Crystal Palace? What do you like most about the area?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;We’re actually based north of the river. I used to come here a lot. I had a few friends living in the area and I love how green it is, more or less as soon as you come out of the station. A couple years back I went to the Aviva Grand Prix at the Sports Centre with my Mum and cuz. We loved it, great advert for the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we can expect from your set at the Festival?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;We&amp;#39;re gonna bring the sunshine :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look out for John Blood and the Highlys playing on Saturday 16th June in Westow Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/EKRoh8tF6Lk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;463&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>We have a festival app! How cool is that?</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-06-05-we-have-a-festival-app-how-cool-is-that"/>
			<updated>2012-06-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-06-05-we-have-a-festival-app-how-cool-is-that</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After visiting Glastonbury last year for the umpteenth time, I thought how brilliant their app was and how cool would it be if we had a Crystal Palace Overground Festival app? And lo it came to pass when I met with Ben from Tens and Units who kindly volunteered to help the festival this year. After much work from Ben and his partner James, we tested it out and moved all the pins around, updated the database a few times (tedious work but well worth it) and now it’s launched! All you have to do is go to iTunes and type Crystal Palace Overground Festival in the search and then you can download it for free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies to all other smartphone users but we unfortunately didn’t have the time or resources to develop the app for other platforms. Maybe next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The map has all the festival venues, and the sponsors and advertisers who supported the festival on it. You can also view all of the artists and venues in more detail on the other pages. We are so excited about the app and thank Ben and James for all their hard work which they did for free! How cool is that? We are constantly amazed at how much the people of Crystal Palace do for the love of this fantastic place and this is just another great example of that dedication. Go Crystal Palace!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tensandunits.com/&quot; title=&quot;Ben&amp;#39;s website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tensandunits.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.tensandunits.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Our interview with Jim Bob</title>
			<link href="http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-05-21-our-interview-with-jim-bob"/>
			<updated>2012-05-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
			<id>http://crystalpalacefestival.org/blog/2012-05-21-our-interview-with-jim-bob</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any terrifying music teachers we have to thank for your pop career? How did you get your start in music?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wasn’t terrifying, but my music teacher Mr Daley played guitar at my first ever live performance when I was about fifteen. There were three of us in the band. And Mr Daley. He held it all together as he was the only one who could actually play. My daughter went to the same school and years later I went back as a parent and Mr Daley was still there. I was too timid to talk to him. There was also a guitar teacher but I gave up after two lessons because I wanted to play Summertime Blues, not Streets of London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you always think you’d end up playing in bands? What was the moment with your first band, Jamie Wednesday, when you knew music was what you wanted to do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew at school, years before. Also, when I saw the film Stardust with David Essex and wanted to be him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give us an idea of what it was like in the London pop scene in the nineties. What was it like following the Brit Pop boom?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My success with Carter came before the Brit Pop years. It’s the first few years of the nineties that have been written out of musical history. Judging by the musical output of BBC4. The scene I was a part of was spread across the country and I remember touring and playing outside London more fondly in a way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Having said that, Carter the Unstoppable Sex Machine had plenty of success and still sells out major venues like Brixton Academy! You obviously attracted a dedicated audience somewhere in those 14 top 40 singles and the number one album – are you finding that it’s mostly original fans or have you picked up new followers along the way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are definitely some new people. They may be kids of fans I suppose but I think people can discover music from the past and find it exciting, they don’t have to have been there at the time it was created. The band do tend to be the oldest people in the building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your bio says that Carter USM was known for ‘a use of puns’. Did that flair for wordplay inspire you to write your two novels?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think so. I’ve always liked words. With the novels I’ve had a lot of people talking about whether songwriting musicians can write books. But to me they seem the likeliest people to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It seems like you’ve dabbled in writing songs for the stage as well as writing for the screen – did you fall into writing from songwriting or was it something you always thought you might end up doing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing songs when I was a teenager and most of the other more varied things I’ve written for, I’ve stumbled into by chance. I wrote two songs for a pantomime at the Barbican for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can people expect from your novels?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big thing people seem to pick up on is that they’re funny and dark. Black comedy. And there are illustrations, which keep being referred to as crude, which I can’t really argue with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you always lived south of the river? As someone who’s only recently arrived here (moved to the area about 2 months ago!) I am overwhelmed by the amount of creativity at my doorstep. What do you think that says about South London? What are your favourite things about Crystal Palace?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have. I was born in Streatham and have never lived further than a few miles away. I’ve been in Crystal Palace for years. It’s changed massively. I think for the better. I’ve always said I don’t really like South London and want to move away but then get incredibly defensive if people (usually from North London) slag it off. I like Crystal Palace at the weekend when it becomes a bit like a busy village.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
</feed>